AHSAN SHAH FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Experienced JavaScript React Developer with 7+ years in the Industry, armed with experience in implementing highly responsive user interface components by deploying React concepts. Adapt at improving front-end performance by testing and debugging codes to boost overall performance by 20%. Friendly and engaging, excited to learn, and happy to mentor and share knowledge with colleagues.



PHONE

EMAIL

+1 662 278 0776

devs.ahsan@gmail.com



ADDRESS

181 Gilla Dr Ballwin, MO



LINKEDIN

www.linkedin.com/in/ahsan-shahid-0a6156253/

PORTFOLIO

https://ahsan-sha.github.io/Portfolio/

EXPERTISE

- React.is
- Redux
- Redux Saga
- CSS/SCSS
- Semantic UI
- Next Js
- Vue Js
- Material UI
- React Native
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- Ant Design
- Typescript
- Express Node js
- StoryBook
- Jest
- ES6
- HTML
- Cypress
- PHP
- Laravel

EDUCATION

SEPTEMBER 2011 - APRIL 2014 BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCES

University of Arkansas







WORK EXPERIENCE

2019 - 2022

WebFx

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Built rich prototypes and applications using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, JSON, React Js, Angular
 and Bootstrap.Time Manager Leadership Integrity Communicate
- Worked with Node.js to develop RESTful API's consumed in front end applications
- Implemented MVP architecture using Redux Architecture with React JS.
- $\bullet \qquad \text{Worked with JASMINE unit test framework to write unit tests for JavaScript code}.$
- Developed various screens for the front end using React JS and used various predefined components from NPM (Node Package Manager)
- Developed data formatted web applications and deploy the script using client- side-scripting using JavaScript
- Documented and maintained reports of all coding and flow structure and presented them to the company.
- Used \$localStorage, \$sessionStorage to manage the data in the project by storing the data in local storage, session storage of the browser.

2016 - 2019

Fintron Invest

SENIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER

- Translating designs & amp; wireframes into high-quality code and writing application interface code via React workflows
- Refactored codebase with React Hooks to increase modularity, reduce duplicate stateful logic, and avoid having to create complex components, thus allowing for faster development by 38%
- Assisted in A/B testing of different UX components that resulted in a 25% increase in customer satisfaction rates.
- Built a unit testing and integration infrastructure using Jest and Cypress that reduced reports of bugs by 10%

CERTIFICATION

Microsoft Certified Specialist with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript

Adobe Certified Expert

Zend Certified PHP Engineer

HOBBIES





Camera

Music





Read

Trave

FREELANCE WORK EXPERIENCE

2022 - PRESENT

Optimizer LLC

FULL STACK REACT | FRONTEND DEVELOPER

- Manage web development and Cross platform mobile apps from initial design until completion with 100% deadline adherence
- Introduced wider use of isomorphic React and Node.js for web applications, decreasing load times by roughly 35%
- Project: PDF Acrobat forms automation in React by utilizing custom libraries.
- Swipefox (swipefox.com)

2022 - 2023

Metroclick LLC

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Using the MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js) stack, I developed and maintained scalable online apps to guarantee great speed and usability.
- RESTful APIs were implemented, and third-party services were integrated for improved functionality.
- Developed user interfaces that are responsive and simple using cutting-edge front-end frameworks like Angular and React.

2015 - 2016

Globewyze LLC

NEXTJS (TYPESCRIPT) | FRONTEND DEVELOPER (PROJECT BASED)

- Developed the Frontend, utilizing React libraries such as Next and Gatsby.
- Converted the design comp into reusable code.
- Projects: CryptohuntGo, thekraft.io.

PORTFOLIO



https://ahsan-sha.github.io/Portfolio/

MY RECENT PROJECTS:

https://yogainternational.com/

https://skillgigs.com/

https://www.luckytruck.com/

https://swipefox.com/







